<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Unique Meat Flavors</name>
  <author>Joa</author>
  <packageId>joa.uniquemeatflavors</packageId>
  <url>https://github.com/joa/unique-meat-flavors</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <description>Every new game randomly assigns a flavor to each animal species in your world — vanilla, DLC, and modded animals included. When a colonist eats meat (raw or in a meal), they gain an extra mood thought based on the species' flavor.

Five tiers: Bland (-3), Common (silent), Tasty (+2), Delicious (+4), Exquisite (+6). The distribution is centered on Common, so most species are unremarkable and the extremes are rare. Flavors are saved per game — a Thrumbo that's exquisite in one playthrough might be bland in the next.

WHY THIS EXISTS

This is my first RimWorld mod. I built it because my partner and I play long multiplayer campaigns together, and I wanted something small that adds a bit of personality to the food economy without changing how the game plays.

Multiplayer compatibility was a design constraint from day one, not a patch tacked on later: per-save settings travel with the host, re-rolls and toggles propagate to every client via SyncMethod, all randomization goes through RimWorld's seeded RNG. If you play MP with someone, this should just work.

FEATURES
- Per-save randomization
- Inspect strings on meat stacks show the flavor
- Meals with mixed meat average their flavors (non-meat ingredients ignored)
- Modded animals supported — any meatDef gets a flavor automatically
- Mid-campaign safe — add an animal mod later and its meats get flavors on next load
- Bilingual: English / Spanish
- Multiplayer compatible (Zetrith's Multiplayer): host-authoritative settings, fully synced

SETTINGS
- Cosmetic-only mode (mood off, flavors still visible)
- Mood magnitude multiplier: 0.5x / 1x / 2x
- Re-roll all flavors button

Bug reports and source: github.com/Joaprzp/unique-meat-flavors
License: MIT. Required: Harmony.

---------- Español ----------

Cada partida nueva asigna aleatoriamente un sabor a cada especie animal de tu mundo — vanilla, DLCs y mods incluidos. Cuando un colonista come carne (cruda o en un meal), recibe un thought extra de humor según el sabor de la especie.

Cinco niveles: Insípido (-3), Común (silencioso), Sabroso (+2), Delicioso (+4), Exquisito (+6). La distribución está centrada en Común, así que la mayoría de las especies son intermedias y los extremos son raros. Los sabores se guardan por partida: un Thrumbo exquisito en una partida puede ser insípido en la siguiente.

POR QUÉ EXISTE

Este es mi primer mod de RimWorld. Lo hice porque con mi pareja jugamos campañas largas en multiplayer, y quería algo chico que le diera un poco de personalidad a la comida sin cambiar la forma de jugar.

La compatibilidad con multiplayer fue un requisito desde el día uno, no un parche puesto al final: los settings viajan con el host, los re-rolls y los toggles se propagan a todos los clientes vía SyncMethod, y toda la aleatorización pasa por el RNG sincronizado de RimWorld. Si jugás MP con alguien, esto tiene que funcionar.

CARACTERÍSTICAS
- Re-randomización en cada partida
- Inspect strings muestran el sabor en cada stack de carne
- Meals con carnes mezcladas promedian sus sabores (los ingredientes no-carne se ignoran)
- Soporta mods de animales — cualquier meatDef recibe sabor automáticamente
- Seguro mid-campaign — agregá un mod de animales después y sus carnes reciben sabor en el próximo load
- Bilingüe: Inglés / Español
- Compatible con Multiplayer (Zetrith): settings host-authoritative, totalmente sincronizado

CONFIGURACIÓN
- Modo solo cosmético (sin humor, sabores siguen visibles)
- Multiplicador de magnitud: 0.5x / 1x / 2x
- Botón de re-randomizar todos los sabores

Bug reports y código: github.com/Joaprzp/unique-meat-flavors
Licencia: MIT. Requerido: Harmony.</description>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
    <!-- Soft hints. These mods are NOT required for the mod to work; they
         only need to load before us when present, so MP's sync system is
         initialized before our HarmonyInit calls MP.RegisterAll. -->
    <li>zetrith.prepatcher</li>
    <li>rwmt.Multiplayer</li>
  </loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>
